Preliminary Guide to the Germanic Studies Department records, 1970-1995 RG0009
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Germanic Studies Department records
1970-1995
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
RG0009
5.21 Linear Feet
Materials in this collection include budgets, departmental business, correspondence and reading exam results. The collection covers the years 1970 to 1995.
Restrictions on Access
Student records in Series 1 are restricted for 100 years from date of record creation or until the death of the student. Access to student records is governed by the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which protects the privacy of student education records.
Acquisition Information
Acquisition data is unknown.
Historical or Biographical Note
The Germanic Studies Department is today the German and Slavic Languages and Literatures Department.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include budgets, departmental business, correspondence and reading exam results. The collection covers the years 1970 to 1995.
Collection Organization
Organized in two series: Administrative records and Records.
George Washington University. Dept. of German and Slavic Languages and Literatures; George Washington University
- Administrative records, 1970-1995; RG0009 Series 1; 6 Linear feet
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access to student records is governed by the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which protects the privacy of student education records. Student records are closed for 100 years from date of record creation.
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes budgets, departmental business, correspondence, reading exam results and other administrative records from 1970-95.
  Formerly ACC#623
  - Annual Gift to Alumni Fund, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports, full time faculty, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Appointment, Promotion and Tenure, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Asskaryak, Farhad A., undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Asskaryak, Farhad A., undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Avanesova, Osanna, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bailey, Stephen, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Baldwin, Andrew S., undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Botinger, Heinrich C., undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bowman, Laura, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Budget Printouts, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Budget Printouts, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Burns, Christine L. - Grad., undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Breneman, Astrid M., undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Campbell, Roger, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Catalogue, Bulletin Copy, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - CCAS Council of Chairs, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - CCAS Committee on Foreign Language Teaching, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Combredet, Lauren, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Commission for the Year 2000, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Committee on Foreign Language Teaching [1/2], undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Committee on Foreign Language Teaching [2/2], undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Computer/Word Processor, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Continuing Departmental Business [1/3], 1992 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Continuing Departmental Business [2/3], 1992 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Continuing Departmental Business [3/3], 1992 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Continuing Departmental Business - important [1/5], 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Continuing Departmental Business - important [2/5], 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Continuing Departmental Business - important [3/5], 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Continuing Departmental Business - important [4/5], 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Continuing Departmental Business - important [5/5], 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Continuing Departmental Business - important [1/6], 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Continuing Departmental Business - important [2/6], 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Continuing Departmental Business - important [3/6], 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Continuing Departmental Business - important [4/6], 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Continuing Departmental Business - important [5/6], 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Continuing Departmental Business - important [6/6], 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Important Documents, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence [1/2], 1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Important Documents [2/2], 1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence [1/2], 1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Important Documents [2/2], 1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Important Documents [1/2], 1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Important Documents [2/2], 1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence [1/5], 1992 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence [2/5], 1992 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence [3/5], 1992 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence [4/5], 1992 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence [5/5], 1992 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence [1/4], 1993 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence [2/4], 1993 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence [3/4], 1993 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence [4/4], 1993 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence [1/4], 1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence [2/4], 1994 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence [3/4], 1994 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence [4/4], 1994 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence Important Documents [1/3], 1990-1995 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence [2/3], 1995 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence [3/3], 1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dallmeyer, Bree, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Demmert, Jennifer, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Departmental Inventories, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Department Budget, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Department Select Items, 1983-1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Department Summer, 1989-1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dettwiler, Bettina S., undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Egan, Kenneth, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Ferrer, Marta, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Fletcher, Samuel A., undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Five Year Plan, 1988-1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Foreign Study Brochures and Information, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Full-Time Support Position, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Garfield, Rene, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - General Education Requirements CCAS, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Germaine, Lindsey B., undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - German Area Studies, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - German Club- German Club Constitution, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - German Club- Release from Liability Forms, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - German Course Descriptions, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - German Majors and Minors, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - German Reading Examinations for Grad. Students, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Glickman, Deanna, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Goetter, Claudia E., undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Gottschall, Jennifer, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Gramer, Jan S., undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Hazardous Material, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Heerman, Katherine, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Helmstetler, Friedrich, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Henderson, Alexander C., undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Hennip, Tina, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Hyde, Donald C., undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Ittner, John B. Grad., undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Kahls, Robert, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Kero, Kenneth, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Kevorkian, Christopher, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Koval, Nedjma, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Krefski, Michele H., undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - LaFollette, Lisa, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Language Laboratory, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - LaRosa, Jennifer A. - Grad., undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Lind, Emily J., undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Lippincott, Aura L., undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Liu, Nancy, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Lubeck, Thomas, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Lukaczyk, Tamara A., undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Mandry, Magaarete M., undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Medhane, Saba, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Microcomputer Hardware, undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Minasova, Marina, undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Misra, Amit, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Moore, Lawrie, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Murphy, James J. M.A., undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Mundt, Alexander, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Nagle, John J., undated (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Nesta, Nicolas, undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Niedergesahs, Karin, undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Nilufer, Mirel, undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Nordhougen, Steven G., undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Orquiza, Alan, undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Palmer, Thomas S., undated (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Perotto, Roseann, undated (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Personal computers, undated (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Ploetz, Janine, undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Placement Tests, undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Postage, undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Prospective Part-time Instructors, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Rak, Adam, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Reading Exam Results, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Reading Exam Results, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Reading Exam Results, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Reading Exam Results, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Reading Exam Results, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Reading Exam Results, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Reading Exam Results, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Reading Exam Results, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Reading Exam Results, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Registration Data, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Roch, Robin, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Roman T. Haueis, Grad., undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Ruedel, Bettina, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Rydlova, Petra, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Ruth Beka Request, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Scandinavia, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Schedule of Classes, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Schoenfeld and Buka Prizes, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Secretarial Aides, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Sehrt Tuition Awards and Book Gifts, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Self Study Phase 2 Dept. Meetings, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Shaffner, Mary, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Solin, Allison L., undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - SPIA Reading Exam Forms, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Stavenas, Harold O., undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Sternal, Paul K., undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Stong, Matthew H., undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Strassel, Stephanine M., undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Student Evaluation of Teaching Effectiveness, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Subcommittee on Columbian College Chairs, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Subcommittee on Columbian College Chairs, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Subcommittee on Culture, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Summer Program in Europe, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Summer Sessions, Campus, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Texts in German and English: Poems, Songs, Stories, etc., undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Todd, Audrey J., undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Ullah, Mosammat K., undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Ulrey, Stefanie A. - Grad., undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Undergraduates Majors, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - University Mail Service, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - University Owned Equipment Inventory Forms, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Validating Examinations German 1,2,3,4,9,10, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - VauEerden, Karen, undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Wilez, Anita, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Williamson, Wendy, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Wilson, John R., undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Winje, Carolyn J., undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Wit, Adam C., undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Wos, Adriania A., undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Yates, Brian, undated (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Zierler, Matthew, undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Records, 1967-1990; RG0009 Series 2; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series includes fliers, brochures, announcements, etc. relating to Slavic Languages, and documents related to the founding and administration of the GWU chapter of Delta Phi Alpha.
  Formerly vertical files.
  - Slavic Languages and Literatures, Department of, 11/08/1971-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Societies--Honor/Professional--Delta Phi Alpha, 09/25/1967-10/05/1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)